Zack, Arnold Additional Arbitration Cases 5950
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Cases
1984-1999
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Zack, Arnold M.
5950
14 cubic feet
14 linear ft.
Records (documents).
5736602
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, December 02, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 18, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Lawyer, arbitrator, and government official; LLB Yale, 1956, MBA Harvard, 1961, MA Harvard, 1963.
Arnold Marshall Zack is an arbitrator and mediator. Beginning his labor career as a part-time election examiner for the National Labor Relations Board and as a case analyst for the U.S. Wage Stabilization Board (1950-1953), he was also a lecturer in labor economics at Simmons College, Northeastern University (1957-1963); an assistant to Saul Wallen, arbitrator, (1956-1960); director of the Labor-Management Institute of the American Academy of Arbitrators (1966-1968); and has served in various labor-related international posts for the United States government.
Other governmental service includes membership on panels for the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service, the Massachusetts Public Employment Relations Board, the New York State Public Employment Relations Board, The New Jersey Public Employment Relations Board, The New York City Office of Collective Bargaining, and The National Mediation Board. Zack is also a panel member of the American Arbitration Association, and has served as the permanent arbitrator for a number of major corporations and unions and for the State of New York and the U.S. Postal Service.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5512: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 5551: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5620: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5659: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5727: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5281: Arnold Zack Arbitration Files 5786: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5825: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5861: Arnold M. Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5913: Arnold Zack Additional Arbitration Files 5950 P: Arnold Zack Arbitration Cases Photographs
Teachers' unions -- New York (State); Arnold, Zack; United Federation of Teachers. Local 2 (New York, N.Y.)
5736602
- New York City Board of Education vs. UFT Local 2, AFT (Box 1)
  - Charts Related to Teachers (1988-1995) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - UFT - Board of Education Cases (1985-1993) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - YFT/Board of Education - Agreements (1987-1991) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Teacher - Reports (1988-1992) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Teacher - Articles (1988-1993) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Communications (1987-1999) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Employment (1986-1993) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Agreements - General (1987-1994) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Executive Board Minutes (1990) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Education FACTS (1985-1993) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - School Districts (no date) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - PERB Case M-91-080 (1990) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - New York State Emergency Financial Control Board (1992-1996) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - List (no date) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Survey Info (no date) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- New York City Board of Education vs. UFT Local 2, AFT (Box 2)
  - UFT Document Supplement Vol. III (1989-1993) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - UFT & Board of Education of City of New York - Pre-Hearing (1984-1987) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - UFT & Board of Education of City of New York - (1984-1985) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - City of New York Financial Plan Fiscal Year 1993-1996 Vols 1 & 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - UFT & Board of Education of City of New York - Pre-Hearing (1985) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - UFT & Board of Education of City of New York - Supporting Exhibits to Marlene Gold's Testimony (1990-1993) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - UFT Case M92-257 through M92-269 - Pre-Hearing Memorandum (1993) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - UFT Case M92-257 through M92-269 - Post-Hearing Brief (1993) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Clarkstown Teachers; IRS Buffalo; Boston Edison Co. also one vol. of NYS Bd. Of Ed. (Box 3)
  - Board of Education and the City of New York Supporting Documents Vol. I (1975-1993) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Education and the City of New York Supporting Documents Vol. II (1975-1993) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Education and the City of New York Supporting Documents Vol. III (1975-1993) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Clarkstown Suffern, NY Part A (1986-1992) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Clarkstown Suffern, NY Part A (1985-1992) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Burlington RR Northern Co; Clarkson Teachers; Fenn Mftg.; Community Gen. Hosp.; F. DiZoglio & Sons; Federated Lithographers-Printers Inc.; Framingham Firefighters; Brighton Schools; Brockton School; Brockton Housing; Fairbanks Scales; Boston E (Box 4)
  - Clarkstown SD/Clarkstown Teachers Suffern, NY 10/15/92, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fenn Manufacturing/IBEW 8/18/92, New Britain, CT, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Comm General Hosp/SEIU New York, NY 9/21/92, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - F. DiZoglio & Sons/Teamsters #251 6/1/92 Providence, RI, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - East Ramapo /Teachers Assoc. 7/8/92 Spring Valley, NY, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Spring Valley High School 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Town of Exeter 1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Burlington Northern/UTU 7/11/91 Fort Worth, TX, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Burlington Northern/UTU 7/11/91 Fort Worth, TX Public Laws Part 1-Board Papers, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Burlington Northern/UTU 7/11/91 Fort Worth, TX Public Law - Part 2 Board Papers, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Boise Cascade Corp/UPIU 2/26/92 Rumford, ME, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Beth Israel/ Local 1199 3/6/92 New York City, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - BB Rubber Co/URW Nashua, NH (1991-1992) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bay State Gas/USWA 4/1/92 W. Springfield, MA, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - St. Vrain 1989 Negotiations Fact Finding (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Employee Time Card 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Coastal Oil; Greater Lawrence Sanitary Dist.; St. Vrain; Bay State Gas; Boise Cascade; Beth Israel; Beebe Rubber -- photos found in this box are now in 5950 P, box 1, ff2 (Box 5)
  - United Federation of Teachers' Documentary Supplement Vol I. (1991) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - United Federation of Teachers' Documentary Supplement Vol II. (1991) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - United Federation of Teachers' Documentary Supplement Vol IV. (1991) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - United Federation of Teachers' Documentary Supplement Vol V. (1991) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - United Federation of Teachers' Documentary Supplement Hearing Exhibit (1991) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Handy; Hartford; Holyoke Water; Iterlakes School; IRS; James River; Jewish Home; Jones & Lampson; Keene State College; Kinney Vac; Lincoln School; Littleton; Lutheran Medical; Mapleton School; Manchester City; Merrimack Teachers; Milfor Police (Box 6)
  - PERB In the Matter of Impasse between UFT & Board of Education City School District of City of New York (456) - (1993) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - PERB In the Matter of Impasse between UFT & Board of Education City School District of City of New York (726) - (1993) (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - PERB In the Matter of Impasse between UFT & Board of Education City School District of City of New York (933) - (1993) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - PERB In the Matter of Impasse between UFT & Board of Education City School District of City of New York (1225) - (1993) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - PERB In the Matter of Impasse between UFT & Board of Education City School District of City of New York (Jan. 13, 1993) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - PERB In the Matter of Impasse between UFT & Board of Education City School District of City of New York (185) - (1993) (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Boston Edison (1991) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- NYNEX; Park Plaza; Peabody; Perkit; Portsmouth; Plume & Atwood; Presidents Emergency Bd., Amtrak; State of Rhode Island Court Reporters; R.I. Philharmonic; Rochester (NH) Schools; Rock-Tenn; Roger Williams College; Sinai; So. Shore Teachers; N (Box 7)
  - Adams County/District 14 Teachers (1992) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Boston Edison Company Agreements & Arbitrations (1983-1992) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Boston Edison Company - Paperwork (1990-1992) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - East Rampo Teachers Assn (1991-1993) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Brief for the Company (1991) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - IRS, Buffalo District & National Treasury Employees Union (1990-1991) (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - IRS Case Notes & Letters (1990-1991) (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - IRS Case Attachments & Agreements (1985-1989) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - IRS Case Attachments & Agreements (1985-1989) (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - IRS Case Attachments & Agreements (1985-1989) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- A&B Railroad (1992) (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Fairbanks Scales/UE Local 234 9/29/92 St. Johnsbury, VT, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Brockton Housing/SEIU 11/13/92 AAA Boston, MA, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Brockton School/Ed. Assoc. 12/3/92 Brockton, MA, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Brighton Schools/Teachers Assoc. 11/17/92 Brighton, CO, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Framingham/Firefighters 10/2/92 Letters, Memos & Notes, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Framingham/Firefighters 10/2/92 Legal Docs, Agreements & Reports, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Fed. Litho/GCIU 11/12/92 Cranston, RI, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Railroad Documents (1992) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Coastal Oil/Teamsters #25 AAA, Boston 9/30/92 Notes & Files, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Coastal Oil/Teamsters #25 AAA, Boston 9/30/92 Legal Documents, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Bay State Gas Company Inspectors Daily Report (1990) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Employee Time Cards (1990) (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Washington, DC Teachers Union (1990) #1 Rick's Case (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Washington, DC Teachers Union (1990) #2 Rick's Case (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Washington, DC Teachers Union (1990) #3 Ricks Case (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Washington, DC Teachers Union - Notes & Letters (1990) (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Greater Lawrence Sanitary District - Arbitration (1991) (Box 10, Folder 5)
- District of Columbia Public Schools (1985) (Box 10, Folder 6)
- National Alliance of Federal & Postal Employees (1988) (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Exeter/Firefighters 6/23/92 Exeter, NH, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Best Foods 1992 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Original Bradford Soap/Teamsters #64 TBD 10/8/92, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Hardy & Harman/USWA Bridgeport, CT 8/14/92, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Hartford Board of Ed./Fed of Teachers 12/16/92 Hartford, CT, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Hillcrest Hosp./MNA 11/30/92 Boston, MA AAA, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Hollis School/Hollis Support Staff 7/18/91 Hollis, NH Notes & Forms, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Hollis School/Hollis Support Staff 7/18/91 Hollis, NH Legal Documents, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Holyoke Water/IBEW 1/20/92 Chicopee, MA, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Interlake's School/Ed. Assoc. 8/4/92 Meredith, NH, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- IRS/NTEU Brooklyn, NY 12/7/92, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Jaffrey - Rindge Fact finding 7/26/91, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Jaffrey - Rindge Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Background, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Jaffrey - Rindge Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Grievance Procedure, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Jaffrey - Rindge Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Medical Insurance, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Dental Insurance, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Salary, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Nurses, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Comp for Comm Work, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 19)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Just Cause, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 20)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Professional Devel., 1991 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Reduction in Force, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Jaffrey - Rindge - Fact Finding 7/26/91 - Working Conditions, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- James River/Int'l Printing & Graphics 8/22/91 Harrisburg, PA, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- James River/UPIU 61 3/4/92 Groveton, NH, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 25)
- James River Corp/UPIU 8/11/92 E. Pepperell, MA 01463, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 26)
- Jewish Home, NEHCEU/SEIU 3/4/92 Providence, RI, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 27)
- Jewish Home/NEHCEU 5/8/92 Providence, RI, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 28)
- Jones & Lampson/UE #218 Springfield, VT 9/23/92, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 29)
- Keene State Col/UNA Fact Finding 12/8/92 ???, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 30)
- Keene State College - Post hearing Brief 1/14/93, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 31)
- Kinney Vac/UAW Canton, MA 6/3/92, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 32)
- LaConia School/Educ. Assoc. Fact Finding 1/8/92 NH, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Lincoln School Committee/Teachers Assoc. 10/28/92Providence, RI AAA Office, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Littleton/NEA NH 2/10/92 Gilford, NH, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Littleton/SEA 6/29/92 Littleton, NH, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Littleton School/Littleton Teachers 11/20/92 Littleton, MA, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Luthern Medical Center/Local 1199 6/26/92 NY, NY, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Mapleton School District/ Education Association 6/23, 24, 25 1992 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- City of Manchester/IAFF 2/7/92 Manchester, NH, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- City of Manchester 1992 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Merrimack/Teachers Assoc. 6/3/92 Manchester, NH, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- City of Milford/Milford Police 5/18/92 Milford, MA, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- NH Dept. of Educ. V. SEA Berwick by Briefs (1992) (Box 12, Folder 12)
- New England Frozen Foods/Truck Drivers 5/11/92 Auburn, MA, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- General Dynamics/Local 571 Mystic, CT 3/2-3/3/92, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 14)
- Gen'l Dynamics/Local 571 9/16/92 Mystic, CT, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Great Northern/UPIU 9/27/92 Millinocket. ME, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 16)
- N. Kingstown School/NEA 1/28/92 N. Kingstown, NH, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 17)
- NYNEX/Local 1109 4/24/92 NY, NY, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Park Plaza/HEREIU Boston, MA 12/11/92, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Peabody/ Peabody Police 5/20/92 Peabody, MA, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Perkit Folding Box/UPIU Boston, MA 11/5/92, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Portsmouth Naval/FEMTC 10/13 Location ??, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Plume & Atwood/USWA 10/22/92 Waterbury, CT, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- President's Emergency Board AMTRAK, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- State of RI/RI Court Reporters 11/23/92 Providence, RI, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- RI Philharmonic/Fed. Of Musicians 7/28/92 RI, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Rochester School/Teachers 7/21/92 Rochester, NH, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Roct-Tenn/UPWIU 5/5/92 Burlington, CT, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Roger Williams Col/College Assoc. 1/26/93 Bristol, RI, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Rutland School/Rutland Ed. Assoc. 2/4/92, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 1)
- Salem/S.E.A. Mediation 3/10/92 Salem, NH, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Salem/Salem Firefighters 7/9/92 Salem, NH, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Sheraton/HEREIU 11/16/92, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Simmons College/SEIU Boston, MA AAA Office 11/29/92, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Sinai/SEIU Baltimore, Maryland 7/10/91, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- S. Shore Voc/Teachers Fed 2/24/92 Hanover, MA, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Newton Police/City of Newton 6/12 6/17, 6/19 Newton, MA - Notes, Lists & Memos, 1990-1993 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Newton Police/City of Newton 6/12, 6/17, 6/19 Newton, MA - Reports, 1990-1992 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Newton Police/City of Newton 6/12, 6/17, 6/19 Newton, MA - Legal Documents, 1988-1992 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Newton Police/City of Newton 6/12, 6/17, 6/19 Newton, MA - Articles & Booklets, 1989-1992 (Box 14, Folder 11)
- Alabama Ed. Assoc./Alabama Prof. Staff 11/4-5/92 Alabama, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)